Let's check out one of the most common functions in Spark, Maps.
先来看一下 Spark 最常见的函数 Maps
Maps simply make a copy of the original input data,
Maps 会复制原始输入数据
and transform that copy according to
并把副本数据
whatever function you put inside the map.
按照你在 Map 中的函数进行转换
The term Map comes from the mathematical concept
Map 这个术语来自数学里的概念
of mapping inputs to outputs, not the maps you'd get
将输入映射到输出 而不是指地图
Still you can think about them as directions for
不过你也可以把它看作是
the data telling each input how to get to the output,
把数据从输入数据变换到输出数据的指引
after some initialization to use Spark in our notebook,
在 notebook 中输入一些 Spark 的初始化设置后
we convert our log of songs which is just a normal Python list,
我们把歌曲日志 —— 一个普通的 Python 列表
and to a distributed dataset that Spark can use.
转换为 Spark 可以使用的分布式数据集
This uses the special Spark context object,
这歌转换用到了 SparkContext 这个对象
that is normally abbreviated to SC.
通常缩写为SC
The Spark context has a method parallelize that takes
SparkContext 有一个叫 parallelize 的方法
a Python object and distributes the object
这个方法会把一个 Python 对象分布到
across the machines in your cluster,
群集中的计算机中
so Spark can use its functional features on the dataset.
这样 Spark 就可以把它的函数用在数据集上了
Once we have this small dataset accessible to Spark,
一旦我们可以把 Spark 用在这个小数据集时
we want to do something with it.
我们就可以开始处理它了
One example is to simply convert the song title to
一个简单的例子就是把大写的歌曲标题转换为小写
a lowercase which can be a common pre-processing
数据集通常都会经过这样的预处理步骤
step to standardize your data.
使数据标准化
You wouldn't want to get the play count wrong,
标准化数据有助于歌曲次数的正确统计
just because some people enter the song with uppercase
因为有些人用大写字母输入歌曲名称
while others use lowercase.
而有些人使用小写输入
To do this, we can write a very simple Python function
为此 我们可以写一个很简单的 Python 函数
that converts the song to lowercase
将歌曲名称都转换为小写
using Python's built in lower function.
我们用到的函数是 Python 内置的 lower 函数
Next, we'll use the Spark function map
接下来 我们将使用 Spark 函数 map
to apply our converts song to lowercase function
把 converst_song_to_lowercase 这个函数应用于
on each song in our dataset.
数据集中的每首歌曲中
You'll notice that all of these steps
所有这些步骤看上去是立即运行的
appear to run instantly but remember,
但实际上
the spark commands are using lazy evaluation,
spark 使用的是延迟计算
they haven't really converted the songs to lowercase yet.
Spark 还没有将歌曲转换为小写
So far, Spark is still procrastinating to transform the songs to lowercase,
到目前为止 Spark 还在等待将歌曲转换为小写
since you might have several other processing steps like removing punctuation,
因为可能会有其他处理工作 如删除标点符号
Spark wants to wait until the last minute to see if they can streamline its work,
Spark希望等到最后 看看是否可以简化工作
and combine these into a single stage before getting the actual data.
若可以 Spark 会将这些工作先合成一个阶段，再去处理数据
If we want to force Spark to take some action on the data,
如果我们想强制让 Spark 对数据进行操作
we can use the Collect Function which gathers the results
我们可以使用 Collect 函数
from all of the machines in our cluster
这个函数会把集群中的所有机器的结果
back to the machine running this notebook.
收集到运行 notebook 的机器上
Also, keep in mind that Spark didn't mutate the original dataset we gave it.
另外 Spark 并没有改变原始数据集
Spark made a copy of the dataset,
Spark 会拷贝原始数据集
but left the original distributed song log with all of its uppercase letters.
保持原始分布歌曲日志的大写字母不变
So that's Maps, they're pretty simple
这就是 Maps  的过程 很简单
but they play a big role in Spark programming,
但在 Spark 编程中有重要作用
but if you're like me, you probably found it a little
如果你和我一样觉得
annoying to create a brand new Python function,
创建一个全新的 Python 函数
convert song to lowercase,
来转换歌曲名称的大小写太过麻烦
just to use Python's built-in lower function,
你也可以直接用 Python 内置的 lower 函数
the code to define and call the function
因为用于定义和调用函数的代码
was longer than the core logic inside it.
比它里面的核心逻辑还要长
Fortunately Python has a nice feature
幸运的是 Python有一个很赞的函数
from functional programming called Anonymous Functions
该函数来自函数式编程 叫做匿名函数
which don't require you to define a new function for small pieces of code.
它不需要给小块代码定义新函数名称
So you use anonymous functions in Python,
在Python中使用匿名函数时
use this special keyword Lambda,
用 Lambda 这个特殊的关键字
and then write the input of the function followed by a colon,
然后写函数的输入
and the expected output.
后跟冒号和期望的输出
In other words, the left side of the colon is
换句话说 冒号的左边是
the input argument that you'd put it into the function definition,
函数的输入参数
and the right side is what you would return in the function.
右边是函数的返回结果
Since this is a lot more convenient,
因为这个方法很方便
you'll see anonymous functions all over the place in Spark.
所以匿名函数在 Spark 里用的非常频繁
They're completely optional, you could just define functions if you prefer,
至于你是否要用匿名函数 完全取决于你的偏好
but there are best-practice, and small examples like these.
但有很多最佳案例和小例子都会使用匿名函数
Also, you'll often see examples with more concise inputs like X, which also works.
此外  很多示例会用更简洁的输入名称 如X
However, I prefer more expressive argument names
但是 我个人偏好输入名称内容更有意义些
since they make it easier to read the code and understand
因为这种名称会更利于阅读代码和理解
the logic of what your function is doing with the data.
整个函数对数据处理的逻辑